# JADE BARBEN

## Software Developer

(435) 890-8932 · barbenjade@gmail.com Linkedln: www.linkedin.com/in/jade-barben-bb954a87

Portfolio: jadebarben.colutah.org/portfolio/index.html

## **About Me**

I have had the privilege of learning software development part time for over 2 years, and I have recently been training at an accelerated tech training program to deepen my understanding of computer coding. I have been creating professional and mock projects using languages such as, HTML, SCSS, JavaScript, REACT.js, Python, PHP, Git, MongoDB, SQL, Apache, and PowerShell.

# **Example Projects**

	•	
1.	Portfolio Website	<ul> <li>URL: jadebarben.colutah.org/portfolio/index.html</li> <li>Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Flex-box</li> </ul>
2.	React Mad Libs Project	<ul><li>URL: github.com/barbenjade/bottega-madlibs</li><li>Used: REACT.js, CSS, Git, PowerShell</li></ul>
3.	Green Ridge Website	<ul><li>URL: jadebarben.colutah.org/gr/greenR.html</li><li>Used: HTML, SCSS, JavaScript, jQuery</li></ul>
4.	PHP Database Web App	<ul> <li>URL: jadebarben.colutah.org/PHP/database</li> <li>Used: HTML, CSS, Flex-box, SQL, PHP</li> </ul>
5.	React Facebook Project	<ul> <li>URL: github.com/barbenjade/facebook_app</li> <li>Used: REACT.js, JavaScript, Git, GitHub</li> </ul>

# **Employment History**

## Account Manager Green Ridge Landscaping

**Apr 2017 to Jul 2018** 

- · Improved estimation process for landscape projects by creating autofill excel spreadsheets
- · Achieved client satisfaction through communication and prompt response to their needs

## Administrative Assistant Residence Inn by Marriott

Feb 2016 to Sep 2017

- · Trained new receptionists to check guest ledger, rate variance reports, and do other tasks
- · Mastered hotel computer software to monitor hotel occupancy and revise guest folios

#### <u>Technical Operator</u>

#### Brigham Young University

Jun 2013 to Apr 2017

- · Managed BYU's 560-acre campus for pests by using spray equipment to apply pesticides
- · Calculated chemical application rates to add and mix chemicals in spray equipment

## **Lab Tech Support**

## Snow College

Aug 2012 to May 2013

- · Diagnosed and resolved internet connection issues in the computer lab with students
- · Assisted students with issues regarding printing, internet, and computing basics

### **Education**

Brigham Young University	Degree in Landscape M.	Aug 2013 to Apr 2017
Bachelors in Life Sciences	Provo, UT	
Salt Lake Community College	Certificate in Proficiency	May 2017 to Jul 2018
Web Developer	Salt Lake City, UT	
UVU Accredited Tech Training	Certificate of Proficiency	Jul 2018 to Oct 2018
Full Stack Web Developer	Lehi, UT	